girlguiding.org.uk 2019-12-02

# Privacy notice | Girlguiding

Girlguiding is committed to protecting your privacy. This notice details the information we collect from you when you access the Girlguiding website and the steps we take to ensure this information remains confidential.

We all give our personal data out daily – our names, contact details, or other bits of information – and most of us want to be feel sure that our data is being handled properly.

As someone who is in contact with Girlguiding, you may have given us information about yourself, like your name, or email address, or other details. Our privacy notice explains what Girlguiding does with this information – it tells you how we gather, use, disclose and manage your personal data.

We take your privacy very seriously. We aim always to be clear to you about the way Girlguiding manages data, so we make sure our privacy notice is up to date. You should read this page from time to time to check that you are happy with any changes we make.

Our privacy notice is as comprehensive as possible, but it doesn’t cover every aspect of our collection and use of personal data. Please contact us if you need more information, or have any questions about this notice. Our contact details are in the ‘Get in touch’ section below.

## What do: ‘Girlguiding’, ‘we’ or ‘us’ refer to?

In this notice ’Girlguiding’, ‘us’, ‘we’ and ‘our’ refer to the registered charity, The Guide Association (no. 306016 in England, Wales, and Northern Ireland) and our trading subsidiary, The Guide Association Trading Service Ltd (company no. 4301686).

Our registered charity number is 306016 (England and Wales) and SC038436 (Scotland).

Registered / Head office address:  
Girlguiding  
17-19 Buckingham Palace Road  
London, SW1W 0PT

### 

We collect the following personal information (where relevant or applicable):

  * Name
  * Parents’/guardian’s name(s)
  * Contact details, including address, telephone number and email address
  * Date of birth
  * Payment information (bank or credit card details) if you donate to us or buy from our online shop
  * Records of your correspondence with us
  * Records of your participation with us (including as a member or as a volunteer)
  * Donation history and Gift Aid details
  * Information you enter on our website
  * Photographs, video or audio recordings
  * Biographical information
  * Any other information you share with us

This information may be collected from:

  * Information you fill out on the website (including via GO - our volunteer platform, digital forms and online surveys)
  * Telephone or face to face conversations with you and/or your parent/guardian
  * Local or regional Girlguiding groups
  * Third party companies and websites, like Just Giving, Virgin Money Giving and Committed Giving
  * Publicly available sources, like Companies House or the Charity Commission website
  * Communication on social media

We sometimes also collect sensitive personal data, for example information about health, religion, sexuality, ethnicity, political and philosophical beliefs and criminal records. We normally only record this data where we have your consent. But sometimes we are permitted to do this in other circumstances, under data protection law. For example, we may make a record that a person is in a vulnerable circumstance to make sure that we don’t send fundraising messages to them – by doing this we comply with charity law and the Code of Fundraising Practice. 

### 

Data helps us support and improve interactions with Girlguiding. Examples include:

  * Updating you on Girlguiding policies and procedures
  * Providing volunteer care and support
  * Monitoring equal opportunities
  * Managing guiding activities, and making sure the right care is in place for activities
  * Communicating with you, for example when collecting membership details or arranging payments
  * Processing your donation and claiming gift aid
  * Managing fundraising
  * Developing our services
  * Keeping a record of your relationship with Girlguiding for our administration, and to let you know about changes to our services or policies
  * Investigating and responding to complaints, legal claims or other issues
  * Fulfilling your online order for goods or services, including processing payment and letting you know about delivery
  * Carrying out research to improve our services and communications
  * Preventing and detecting fraud and error
  * Assessing applications for volunteering and employment
  * Keeping you up to date with our fundraising and marketing activity through our website, direct mail, SMS/text campaigns, email and telephone (see below for more information)

### **We use marketing materials for the following**

  * Updates about Girlguiding’s work, including newsletters and other publications
  * Appeals and fundraising activities including requests for donations; information about legacy gifts, raising funds or taking part in a fundraising event, and updates on the impact that fundraising activities have had on our work
  * Information about events
  * Information about shop products
  * Volunteering information about how to support Girlguiding, along with updates about the impact of your work

We may also use your personal information to build a profile of your interests and preferences. This helps us send you only relevant and timely information. And building profiles helps us improve the experience our supporters have – if we understand their background we can make appropriate requests to those who may be willing and able to give more than they already do. This helps us raise funds sooner and more cost-effectively.

There’s other information we can use, which is publically available in places like public registers. This can include listed directorships, typical earnings in a geographical area, information from the electoral roll, press reports and social media posts.

### 

Yes! You can withdraw your consent, unsubscribe from or update your marketing preferences at any time. Just use the details in the ‘Get in touch’ section below.

If you make changes to your consent, we will update your record as soon as we possibly can. Emails will be stopped immediately, but it may take up to 60 days for our systems to update and stop post being sent to you.

If you tell us you don’t want marketing, fundraising or campaign communications, you may still receive messages about transactions and services from other connections you have with us (as described below).

You can also opt out of receiving fundraising communications from us by signing up to [the fundraising preference service](https://www.fundraisingregulator.org.uk/the-fundraising-preference-service).

### 

We need a lawful basis to collect and use your personal data under data protection law. The law allows for six ways to process personal data (and additional ways for sensitive personal data). Four of these are relevant to Girlguiding. We can use process information on the basis of:

  * Your consent (for example to send you direct marketing by email or SMS)
  * Your contractual relationship with us (for example to provide you with goods or services that you have purchased from us)
  * The necessity for compliance with a legal obligation (for example to process a gift aid declaration and carrying out due diligence on large donations)
  * Girlguiding’s legitimate interests (please see below for more information)

### 

Personal data may be legally collected and used if it is necessary for a legitimate interest of the organisation using the data, as long as its use is fair and does not adversely impact the rights of the individual concerned.

When we use your personal information, we will always consider if it is fair and balanced to do so, and if it is within your reasonable expectations. We will balance your rights and our legitimate interests to ensure that we use your personal information in ways that are not unduly intrusive or unfair. Girlguiding’s legitimate interests include:

  * Charity governance. This includes delivery of our charitable purposes, statutory and financial reporting and other regulatory compliance purposes and intergroup transfers of data between Girlguiding and our trading subsidiary.
  * Administration and operational management. This includes answering enquires, giving information and services, research, events management, administration of volunteers and employment and recruitment requirements. This involves sharing information with regional and local Girlguiding branches. 
  * Fundraising and campaigning. This includes administering campaigns and donations and sending direct marketing by post (and in some cases making marketing calls), sending thank you letters, analysis, targeting and segmentation to develop communication strategies and maintaining communication suppressions.

If you would like more information on our uses of legitimate interests or to change our use of your personal data please get in touch with us using the details in the ‘Get in touch’ section below.

### 

If you are under the age of 14, you must get permission from your parent or guardian before registering or giving us any information.

### 

Girlguiding keeps your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

We decide how long is appropriate to keep personal data. We do this by considering the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data; the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data; the purposes for which we process your personal data, whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the legal requirements.

If you ask to receive no further contact from us, we will keep some basic information about you on our suppression list to avoid sending you more unwanted messages.

### 

We do not share or sell your personal information to third-party organisations for marketing, fundraising or campaigning purposes.

We share your personal information with our trading company and relevant regional and local Girlguiding organisations to:

  * Administer your membership of Girlguiding
  * Manage your participation in Girlguiding activities
  * Conduct market research so we can improve our offerings to you and as an organisation overall

We share your personal information with an international affiliate of Girlguiding if you tell us you have an interest in joining that international affiliate.

We also share personal information:

  * With data processors working on our behalf. For example, if you buy an item in our online shop, we use a third party to process payments.
  * Where we are required to by law, for example to law enforcement or regulatory bodies
  * Where it is necessary to protect the vital interests of an individual
  * If we have your consent

We may use third-party suppliers to manage events, campaigns or mailings for fundraising appeals; to carry out research surveys or for storage of your personal information on our behalf. You can find out more about the suppliers that we use by contacting us using the details in the ‘Get in touch’ section below.  

We screen and monitor these companies to get the best protection of your privacy and security. They may only use the data in accordance with data protection legislation, under strict instructions from Girlguiding and in accordance with a data processing agreement.

### 

We use technical and organisational ways to protect your data and prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Unfortunately the transmission of data over the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal data we can’t guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website. But once we receive your information we use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We process all credit card payments securely through our secure payment gateway which is PCI DSS Compliant. We do not store credit card details.

We only use the personal information and credit card details that we request to fulfil your order or process your donation.

And we keep the personal information that is required for our accounts secure, and only for as long as required by law.

The information we collect from you may be transferred to and processed and/or stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). If we send your personal data outside the EEA we will take reasonable steps to make sure the recipient uses appropriate measures to protect your information.

### 

 Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used to make websites work more efficiently for visitors, and to provide information to the owners of the site.

We use cookies to:

  * Remember certain information about users so they don’t have to give the same information again
  * Measure how people use our websites so we can improve the way information is provided
  * Display adverts based on what parts of Girlguiding websites people have visited

You agree to our use of cookies by continuing to use our websites. You can find more information on the exact cookies that we use on our ‘Cookies’ page.

### Remarketing

The Girlguiding website may share your personal data with remarketing services - including Facebook, Google Adwords and Google Analytics - to serve our adverts to you on third party websites. Third-party vendors, including Facebook and Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Girlguiding website. Please visit our cookies page for further information.

### 

We cannot be responsible for any information you give in public community areas of the Girlguiding websites, or on websites that we link to from our platforms. This information can be viewed or collected by any third party - you should always be wary of publishing any personal information in public community areas.

You should also read the privacy notices of any other websites that we link to from Girlguiding websites which you visit. This is so you may understand what information is collected from you and for what purpose.

Girlguiding cannot be held responsible for the policies of any third party website that we link to, and you access these websites at your own risk.

## Get in touch with us 

If you have any concerns about the Girlguiding privacy notice or about how we deal with data, or how we’ve used your data, please get in touch. Write to or email the data protection team at:

The data protection officer  
Girlguiding  
17-19 Buckingham Palace Road  
London  
SW1W 0PT

Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7612170217060419021315021f191836111f041a11031f121f18115819041158031d)

We will be happy to help and discuss your concerns.

You can also make a complaint to the[ information commissioner’s office](http://www.ico.org.uk/) and [the fundraising regulator](http://www.fundraisingpreference.org.uk/) .

### Changes to this privacy notice

Keep up to date with changes to this privacy notice by checking the website section from time to time.

© Girlguiding  
17-19 Buckingham Palace Road  
London  
SW1W 0P

Last updated: 23 May 2018

## Explore the Girlguiding site
